[Waco] Jefferson-Moore High School Parent Teacher Association records, Inclusive: 1968-1986, Bulk: 1983-1986
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
[Waco] Jefferson-Moore High School Parent Teacher Association records
Inclusive: 1968-1986, Bulk: 1983-1986
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
2876
Jefferson-Moore High School (Waco, Tex.). Parent-Teacher Association., 1971 - 1986
1 document box
The [Waco] Jefferson-Moore High School Parent Teacher Association records document the involvement of the organization and outline their purpose, goals, and projects in relation to the school. Meeting minutes, including officers, programs, and financial reports, can be found in addition to newsletters and student directories.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Jefferson-Moore High School opened in the Fall of 1971 in Waco, Texas, to replace the former A. J. Moore Junior and Senior High Schools. The establishment of Jefferson-Moore was implemented as the city of Waco desegregated schools and continued with urban renewal.
The Jefferson-Moore High School Parent Teacher Association was established first as the A. J. Moore Jr. and Sr. High School PTA prior to 1968 and then transitioned to the newly established Jefferson-Moore High School in 1971. The organization operated as such until Jefferson-Moore consolidated with Waco High School and Richfield High School in 1986.
Scope and Content
The Jefferson-Moore High School Parent Teacher Association records document the organization first as the A. J. Moore Jr. and Sr. High School PTA in 1968 until that school’s closure in spring 1971. Evidence that the organization operated under the procedures of the National Congress of Colored Parents and Teachers which represented African American children in segregated schools, is present in the minutes. The National Congress of Colored Parents and Teachers unified with the National Congress of Parents and Teachers in 1970. In the fall of 1971, the A. J. Moore PTA was officially transitioned to the Jefferson-Moore PTA and operated as such until the school consolidated with Waco High School and Richfield High School in 1986. Evidence of the impending merger can be seen in the records.
The Administrative series provides the most comprehensive look into activities of the Jefferson-Moore High School Parent Teacher Association. In addition to by-laws, financial reports, and officer notebooks, a ledger of minutes is included. The minutes describe the PTA meetings, as well as highlight concerns of the organization for the students including drug and alcohol use, skipping classes, scholarships, and community care. The organization operated “to promote the welfare of children and youth in home, school, community, and of worship.”
The Publications series holds newsletters and directories. Copies of the school newsletter, The Lion Letter, includes a note from the school principal and information related to important school dates, activities, student concerns, and curriculum. The Jefferson-Moore PTA Newsletter documents the activities of the organization and school in relation to parent participation. The directories provide a snapshot of students at the school during the stated time.
Arrangement
There was no previous discernible arrangement to this collection. Notebooks have been removed from previous three-ring binders and are now in folders titled to reflect their content. Items such as canceled checks and deposit slips have been removed as the same information can be found in the Treasurer’s notebooks. The series is now arranged in two series, Series I: Administrative and Series II: Publications.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 2876. Acquired 1998-07-01
Related Resources
Related references
Hoover, Carl. “East Waco Library features historic black high school, grads.” Associated Press News, December 10, 2018. Accessed 2020 September 7.
“History.” National PTA. Accessed 2020 September 7.
Sawyer, Amanda. “A. J. Moore High School.” Waco History. Accessed 2020 August 26.
“Waco High School” Waco Independent School District. Accessed 2020 August 26.
Index Terms
Subjects
Parents' and teachers' associations -- Texas -- Waco.
Genres
Directories.; Minutes (Records); Newsletters.
- Administrative, 1968-1986; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  The Administrative series, dated 1968-1986, includes a register of minutes, executive committee notebooks, organizational by-laws, financial reports, and limited photographs. The series is arranged in chronological order and is in good condition.
  Index Terms
  Genres
  Photographic print
  - Minutes, 1968-1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Treasurer’s Notebook, 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Photographs (football program), 1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - By-laws, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photographs (football team), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Executive Committee Notebook, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - President’s Notebook, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Treasurer’s Report (Diann Harris), 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General, circa 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Publications, 1983-1986; 2
  The Publications series, dated 1980-1986, includes newsletters and student directories. The series is arranged alphabetically and in good condition.
  - Directory: Senior Cotillion, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Newsletters: Lion Letter, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters: PTA Newsletter, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Student Directories, 1980-1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)